## Matthew J. Krabacher

Cell: +1 (208) 610-5161 | Email: <u>matt.krabacher@gmail.com</u> | Portfolio: <u>mattkrabacher.com</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/mkrabacher</u> | LinkedIn: <u>https://linkedin.com/in/mattkrabacher/</u>

## **Personal Summary**

A full-stack web developer with a year of experience and recent graduate of an immersive 14 week coding program which included 1200 hours of intense study across three different stacks. Proficient in Python, MEAN and C# with the ability to pick up new technologies quickly. Highly motivated and flexible developer that works well in teams or independently. Strong ability to communicate and ownership of responsibilities. A lifelong learner with a drive to affect positive change locally and globally.

## **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C#

#### **Full Stacks**

MEAN, .Net Core, Python

#### Front-End

HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Angular5, AJAX

#### **Back-End**

Node.js, Nginx, AWS, Vim

#### **Database**

SQL(MySQL), SQLite, NoSQL(MongoDB)

#### **Frameworks**

Django, Flask, Express.js, Socket.io, Bootstrap, Entity

#### **Version Control**

GitHub, Git, Unity Collaborate

#### **Concepts**

MVC, OOP, RESTful

#### Wireframe

Balsamiq

# **Highlighted Projects**

## BivyMaps (team of two)

- Web app that displays free user generated camping locations all around the world.
- Users are able to add, edit and delete campsites they created as well as view other users' campsites displayed on an embedded instance of Google Maps with custom icons.

Technologies: Python, Django, MySQL, Google Maps API, JQuery, AJAX

## PsyberWar (team of four)

- Digitized version of a board game currently in development. Players play as either Russia or the US and vie for control of Europe using disinformation and exploiting opponents OpSec.
- Board is animated depending on relevant stats of each player and turns.
  Cards are dealt differently based on turn number.

Technologies: C#, Unity, Unity Collaborate

## **Github Battle** (independent)

- User can compare their GitHub accounts against other users.
- Each user is given a score based upon how many public repos they have and how many users are following them.

Technologies: TypeScript, Angular5, MongoDB, Express.js, GitHub API

# **Terrorism Display** (team of two)

- Visual representation of terrorism data since 1970 with Google Maps Heatmap and Charts.js.
- Data provided by The Global Terrorism Database but hosted locally.
  Over 89000 data points which had to be summarized into 1000 point and formatted for the Google Maps Heatmap layer.

Technologies: TypeScript, Angular5, MongoDB, Express.js, Google Maps API, Charts.js, Studio 3T (MongoDB GUI)

#### **Education**

## **Full Stack Web Developer Coding Bootcamp**

Coding Dojo, Seattle, WA (Dec 2017 - Mar 2018)

Coding Dojo is an immersive web development boot camp specialized in training full stack developers. The Dojo teaches the latest technologies and equips students with the skills to quickly and efficiently learn new technologies to remain relevant in an ever evolving industry. I spent an estimated 1200 hours of study over three stacks to complete each exam (4.5 hours to create a full stack web application from scratch) on the first attempt as well as created a full-scale and deployed project within 5 days for each stack.

Average Exam Scores (out of 10): Python Stack: 9.6; .Net Suite: 9.4; MEAN Stack: 10.0

### **Front End Developer Program**

Free Code Camp (May 2017 – Nov 2017)

Free Code Camp is an online educational platform that teaches Front and Back End web development courses. They have close ties with numerous non-profit organizations and help new developers find work and get experience through volunteering.

# **Professional Experience**

## **Logistics Coordinator**

Northwest Outward Bound School, Redmond, OR, (Apr 2014 – Current)

- Responsible for the organization and delivery of large groups of people to back country settings as well as the maintenance and organization of all equipment at the school.
- Since starting I have now become involved in trainings and taking over responsibilities of the Logistics Manager upon her absence.

## **English Teacher**

Caledonian Language School, Prague, Czech Republic (Oct 2014 – Apr 2015)

 Responsible for meeting students at their chosen place of study and for the preparation and tailoring of each lesson to their specific needs.

#### **Safari Coordinator**

Great Alaska Adventure Lodge, Sterling, AK, (May – Sep. 2013)

- o Coordinated daily safari activities and managed a guide staff of five.
- o Maintained records of all safari expenses and activity in state recreation areas.
- Coordinated all bush flights and resupplies to and from our remote bear viewing camp.

#### **Chairman of the Public Relations Committee**

S.I.B. (Dutch United Nations Student Association in English), The Netherlands, Oct. 2011 – Sep. 2012.

- Managed committee responsible for the advertisement and public image of the SIB. During my time we completed several PR events as well as coordinated with other committees to facilitate their needs for public relations.
- Responsible for the coordination and documentation of meetings with the PR committee as well as regular communication with the SIB Board of Directors.